realtor.org 2005-04-06

# NAR's Privacy Policy Statement

Popular Links

Your Business Tools

Especially for

&nbsp;

Receive customized  
news and, for   
REALTORS®,   
full site access.

**Purchase products**  
from REALTOR VIP®   
Alliance Partners and   
leverage NAR's group   
buying power.

|   
** **|   
12/04/2003

 **Privacy Policy** We recognize the importance of protecting the personal information you provide at Web sites owned and/or controlled by the NATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF REALTORS® (NAR). One of the National Association’s sites, [REALTOR.com](http://www.realtor.com/)[](http://www.commercialsource.com/terms.htm%22target=%22blank), has posted its own "privacy polices" and "terms of use". For the rest of the National Association’s Web sites, we maintain the following privacy policy:1\. We gather the following types of information needed to process your transactions, fulfill your requests, and maintain our membership records:   

  * Contact information you provide (for example, your personal and business addresses, phone and fax numbers, firm affiliations and titles). 
  * Tracking information which our Web server automatically recognizes each time you visit one of our sites or communicate with us by e-mail (for example, your domain name, your e-mail address, and what pages you visit); and
  * Information you volunteer, via applications or surveys (for example, education, designations, specialties, affiliations with other real estate organizations and general demographic data).2\. We use this information to:  

    * Improve and customize the content and layout of our sites and other communications tools, such as REALTOR® Magazine online and print.
    * Notify you of updates to our sites.
    * Notify you of relevant products and services.
    * Notify you of upcoming events and programs. 
    * Compile specialty directories about which you will be made aware.
    * Track usage of our sites.
    * Assist local and state REALTOR® associations and affiliated Institutes, Societies and Councils in membership tracking and for their use for purposes similar to those listed above.3\. NAR does not share, sell or trade e-mail addresses, but may provide you with on-line informational or marketing messages that have been approved by NAR for the purposes described in Part 4 of this policy.4\. We will not share, sell or otherwise provide other information about you to third parties, except for:   

      * Partners in our REALTOR VIP® Program for the limited purpose of notifying you of NAR-approved promotions.
      * Exhibitors at REALTOR® trade shows for the limited purpose of contacting you one time immediately before and after trade shows, through marketing vehicles approved by NAR.
      * Other vendors for the limited purpose of contacting targeted groups of members, through marketing vehicles approved by NAR.
      * When required by law or valid legal process, or to protect the personal safety of our members or the public.
      * Some or all of the data collected during promotions or contests on our sites that are sponsored by third parties may be shared with the sponsor for the limited purpose of a one-time marketing follow-up by the sponsor. If information about you will be shared with a sponsor you will be notified prior to your participation in the promotion or contest and you can decide not to participate in the promotion or contest. 5\. Credit information that you and credit authorizers provide when you make payments by credit card or electronic check for products, dues or other services via the REALTOR® Electronic Commerce Network (“E-Commerce Network”) will only be used to process the transactions you request. This information will be provided to and maintained by reputable credit reporting databases, but will never be sold, shared or provided to other third parties. 6\. We maintain security procedures and standards which we believe are as safe as today’s technology permits. We test these procedures and modify them regularly as new technologies become feasible.7\. We utilize a strict Opt-Out policy for sending online notifications regarding services, products and programs. You may adjust your Communication Preferences by reviewing your REALTOR.org registration. Just Login first. Then you can change your preferences. (Examine and update your existing account).8\. You may edit your personal contact information directly in the NRDS system or by contacting your local REALTOR® association.9\. Some of our sites contain advertising placed by advertising networks pursuant to agreements between the National Association and the advertising network. We do not control these advertising networks, the sites of third parties reached through links on our site or their information collection practices and the National Association will not be responsible for the activities of these third parties. The advertising network uses cookies to collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you click on the banner ads appearing on our sites. This information is collected by the advertising network for purposes of measuring and reporting on the advertising to advertisers and the National Association. The advertising network may also aggregate the information for certain other statistical and reporting purposes.
